Hi, I'm Mark Nelson from the RACF Development Team in Poughkeepsie, New York, and we just
heard Jeff talk about the crypto express card in some of its features.
I'd like to talk about one thing in particular about the crypto express card, and that is
something called secured keys versus protected keys.
Now, when you're using a key, the most important thing you have is keeping that key secure,
private, known only to those people who need to have access to the key.
When you've put a key into the crypto express card, you can put a key in there in a
manner such that it will never, ever, ever leave that card in the clear, ever.
We call that a secured key.
When you're doing cryptographic operations, however, you might want to have the key in storage
for performance reasons.
We'll call that a clear key.
The concept of the clear key doesn't mean that everybody can read it.
It might be in fetch protected storage that only trusted and authorized people within
the ZOS environment can access.
But nonetheless, it's still in storage in the clear, and that represents a bit of risk.
With the crypto express card and something called protected keys, you can get the best of both worlds.
The concept here is that the key that exists in the crypto express card can be wrapped with a
transport key or an L-par specific key, sometimes called it a femoral key, although I hate that word.
But the concept is you can take that wrapped key, transport it over to the ZOS environment,
where it can be used by the CPACF, the central processor assist for cryptographic function.
That is the high-performance cryptographic engine that exists for every central processor in an IBM Z environment.
Now, ZOS can't read that key, but what it can do is pass that wrapped key to the CPACF.
The CPACF can use the key that was used to wrap it, which is available to it because it's the hypervisor.
And then CPACF can do very, very high-performance cryptographic encryption and decryption using that key.
It's really the best of both worlds.